Guide to the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Manuscript Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Chauncey Brewster Tinker manuscript collection
1644-1944
GEN MSS 310
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
9.43
(19 boxes) + 2 volumes and 1 portfolio
Contains chiefly British (as well as other European and American) historical and literary manuscripts and autographs, including items by James Boswell, Jr., Hall Caine, Thomas Frognall Dibdin, John Masefield, Mary Russell Mitford, Richard Brinsley Sheridan, Algernon Charles Swinburne, Anthony Trollope, and John Wilkes.
Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Chauncey Brewster Tinker, 1926-1953.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 21: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Associated Materials
Chauncey Brewster Tinker Papers (GEN MSS 354) and various printed books donated to the Library by Tinker are cataloged separately.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Chauncey Brewster Tinker (1876-1963), Yale Class of 1899, was a member of the Department of English at Yale University, the author of several books about James Boswell, and Keeper of Rare Books in the Rare Book Room at Sterling Memorial Library at Yale. Tinker inspired Frank Altschul to start what later became the Yale Library Associates. Many of the literary and historical manuscripts that Tinker acquired personally he gave to the Yale Library.
For additional information, see the numerous references to Chauncey Brewster Tinker in the index to The Yale University Library Gazette, and the memorial written at the time of his death and printed in the Gazette, Vol. 38, Number 1 (July 1963).
Scope and Contents
This finding aid is a partial regrouping of historical and literary manuscripts from Chauncey Brewster Tinker's personal collection. It does not account for all of the manuscripts given by Tinker to the library. Other groups of Tinker manuscripts (e.g., Arnold, Byron, and Carlyle) remain in previously cataloged collections. Approximately one-third of the manuscripts listed here are described in The Tinker Library: A Bibliographical Catalogue of the Books and Manuscripts Collected by Chauncey Brewster Tinker, compiled by Robert F. Metzdorf (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1959), and are identified here by their Tinker numbers. Other manuscripts in this Collection are not listed in the printed guide and do not have Tinker numbers.
The Collection is arranged alphabetically by author and contains chiefly British, as well as other European and American historical and literary manuscripts and autographs. Each entry in this list was transcribed from the library's card catalog; in some cases, information from entries in the printed guide has been incorporated. Individuals represented in the files include: Matthew Arnold, James Boswell, Jr., Hall Caine, Thomas Frognall Dibdin, John Masefield, Mary Russell Mitford, Alexander Pope, Richard Brinsley Sheridan, Algernon Charles Swinburne, Anthony Trollope, John Wilkes, and William Wordsworth. Many individuals are represented by fewer than five manuscripts, and in many cases by only one. Many of the letters are addressed to William Hepworth Dixon. Oversize material has been housed separately, and cross references have been made. Between 1998 and 2005 additional material was restored to the Tinker Manuscript Collection.
Boswell, James, 1778-1822; Caine, Hall, Sir, 1853-1931; Dibdin, Thomas Frognall, 1776-1847; Masefield, John, 1878-1967; Mitford, Mary Russell, 1787-1855; Sheridan, Richard Brinsley, 1751-1816; Swinburne, Algernon Charles, 1837-1909; Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963; Trollope, Anthony, 1815-1882; Wilkes, John, 1725-1797
- File List, Series I
  - "A"
    - Adam and Charles Black (Firm)
      - 2 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, Edinburgh, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Scope and Contents
        The firm was the publisher of the Encyclopedia Britannica, and the letters constitute a request for an article by Mr. Dixon. His first reply is written on the last leaf of the first letter.
    - Aïdé, Hamilton, 1826-1906
      - ALS to Mr. Neville, London (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Arnold, Frances Lucy (Wightman), d. 1901
      - ALS to Blanche (Smith) Clough, Cobham, Surrey, 1893 Dec 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Tinker 19
      - Lett's diary, or bills due book, and an almanack, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Tinker 20
    - Arnold, Matthew, 1822-1888
      - AMS collection of disjunct leaves, containing first drafts of poems, and prose passages noted for future use, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Tinker 21
      - AMS commonplace book with extracts from Burke, Goethe, Chateaubriand, and other authors, 1847-60, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Tinker 22
      - AMS commonplace book with extracts from his reading in English, Greek, Latin, French, and German, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Tinker 23
      - AMS commonplace book with notes on Homer, Aristotle, Roger Bacon, Humboldt, Teutonic traditions and poetry, the death of Rachel, and other subjects (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Tinker 24
      - Three pocket diaries, 1845-47 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        1845. Goldsmith. An almanack for the year of Our Lord... Tinker 25
        1846. Goldsmith. An almanack for the year of Our Lord... Tinker 26
        1847. Tilt's pocket almanack. Tinker 27
      - Pocket Diaries
        - Allen's commercial diary, almanac, and bill book..., 1852 (Box 2, Folder 10)
          Tinker 28
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1853 (Box 2, Folder 11)
          Tinker 29
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1854 (Box 2, Folder 12)
          Tinker 30
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1855 (Box 2, Folder 13)
          Tinker 31
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1856 (Box 2, Folder 14)
          Tinker 32
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1857 (Box 2, Folder 15)
          Tinker 33
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1858 (Box 2, Folder 16)
          Tinker 34
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1859 (Box 2, Folder 17)
          Tinker 35
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1860 (Box 2, Folder 18)
          Tinker 36
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1861 (Box 2, Folder 19)
          Tinker 37
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 20)
          Tinker 38
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1863 (Box 2, Folder 21)
          Tinker 39
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1864 (Box 2, Folder 22)
          Tinker 40
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1865 (Box 2, Folder 23)
          Tinker 41
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1866 (Box 2, Folder 24)
          Tinker 42
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1867 (Box 2, Folder 25)
          Tinker 43
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1868 (Box 2, Folder 26)
          Tinker 44
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1869 (Box 2, Folder 27)
          Tinker 45
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1870 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          Tinker 46
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1871 (Box 2, Folder 29)
          Tinker 47
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1872 (Box 2, Folder 30)
          Tinker 48
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1873 (Box 2, Folder 31)
          Tinker 49
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1874 (Box 2, Folder 32)
          Tinker 50
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1875 (Box 2, Folder 33)
          Tinker 51
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1876 (Box 2, Folder 34)
          Tinker 52
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1877 (Box 3, Folder 35)
          Tinker 53
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1878 (Box 3, Folder 36)
          Tinker 54
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1879 (Box 3, Folder 37)
          Tinker 55
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1880 (Box 3, Folder 38)
          Tinker 56
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1881 (Box 3, Folder 39)
          Tinker 57
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1882 (Box 3, Folder 40)
          Tinker 58
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1883 (Box 3, Folder 41)
          Tinker 59
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1884 (Box 3, Folder 42)
          Tinker 60
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1885 (Box 3, Folder 43)
          Tinker 61
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1886 (Box 3, Folder 44)
          Tinker 62
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1887 (Box 3, Folder 45)
          Tinker 63
        - Pawsey's London diary, and almanack..., 1888 (Box 3, Folder 46)
          Tinker 64
      - Diaries
        - Lett's diary, or bills due book, and almanac..., 1875 (Box 3, Folder 47)
          Tinker 65
        - Lett's diary, or bills due book, and almanac..., 1876 (Box 3, Folder 48)
          Tinker 66
        - Lett's diary, or bills due book, and almanac..., 1877 (Box 3, Folder 49)
          Tinker 67
        - T.J. & J. Smith's pocket diary and almanack..., 1880 (Box 3, Folder 50)
          Tinker 68
        - T.J. & J. Smith's pocket diary and almanack..., 1881 (Box 3, Folder 51)
          Tinker 69
        - T.J. & J. Smith's pocket diary and almanack..., 1882 (Box 3, Folder 52)
          Tinker 70
        - T.J. & J. Smith's pocket diary and almanack..., 1883 (Box 3, Folder 53)
          Tinker 71
      - AMS of "Stagirius", 1844 (Box 4, Folder 54)
        Tinker 72
      - AMS of "Horatian Echo", 1847 (Box 4, Folder 55)
        Tinker 73
      - AMS of "Memorial Verses. April 27th 1850.", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 56)
        Tinker 74
      - AMS of 15 lines from "Haworth Churchyard", [1855] (Box 4, Folder 57)
        Tinker 75
      - AMS of "Rugby Chapel. November 1857.", ca. 1885 (Box 4, Folder 58)
        Tinker 76
      - AMS of 4 lines from "The Terrace at Berne", 1897 Feb 21 (Box 4, Folder 59)
        Tinker 77
      - ANS, 2 lines from "Obermann Once More", 1884 Mar 7 (Box 4, Folder 60)
        Tinker 78
      - ALS to William Parsons Atkinson, Cobham, Surrey, 1880 Mar 17 (Box 4, Folder 61)
        Tinker 79
      - ALS to Alfred Austin, Cobham, Surrey, 1887 Oct 21 (Box 4, Folder 62)
        Tinker 80
      - ALS to Alfred Austin, Cobham, Surrey, 1887 Oct 28 (Box 4, Folder 63)
        Tinker 81
      - ALS to Alfred Austin, Cobham, Surrey, 1888 Jan 22 (Box 4, Folder 64)
        Tinker 82
      - ANS to J.T. Baron, [London], 1882 Oct 4 (Box 4, Folder 65)
        Tinker 83
      - ALS to Mr. Beale of Banbury, London, 1856 Jan 8 (Box 4, Folder 66)
        Tinker 84
      - ANS to William Cox Bennett, Cohbam, Surrey, [1875?] Jul 10 (Box 4, Folder 67)
        Tinker 85
      - ALS to Mr. Cadbury of Branbury, [London], 1860 Dec 1 (Box 4, Folder 68)
        Tinker 88
      - ALS to Lucy Caroline (Lyttelton) Cavendish, London, [1881?] Mar 3 (Box 4, Folder 69)
        Tinker 89
      - ALS to Chevalier Jean Baptiste François Ernest de Chatelain, London, 1855 Mar 6 (Box 4, Folder 70)
        Tinker 90
      - ALS to Messrs. R. and R. Clark (Edinburgh), Cobham, Surrey, 1888 Mar 1 (Box 4, Folder 71)
        Tinker 91
      - Addressed envelope to "Citizen Clough Oriel Lyceum Oxford", 1848 (Box 4, Folder 72)
        Tinker 92
      - ALS to Sir Sidney Colvin, London, 1887 Jun 28 (Box 4, Folder 73)
        Tinker 93
      - ANS to Mrs. Dickinson, Stockbridge, Mass., [1886] Jul 15 (Box 4, Folder 74)
        Tinker 95
      - AL to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1861 Jun 24 (Box 4, Folder 75)
        Tinker 96
      - ALS to Henry Dunn, [London], 1867 Nov 12 (Box 4, Folder 76)
        Tinker 97
      - ALS to Mary Ann Virginia Gabriel, [London] (Box 4, Folder 77)
        Tinker 99
      - ALS to Arthur Howard Galton, Cobham, Surrey, 1887 Jun 4 (Box 4, Folder 78)
        Tinker 100
      - ALS to Mr. [C.L.?] Graves, Ambleside, 1860 Jul 21 (Box 4, Folder 79)
        Tinker 101
      - ANS to Theophilus Dwight Hall, [London], 1884 May 29 (Box 4, Folder 80)
        Tinker 102
      - ALS to George Macdonald, Harrow, 1868 Apr 3 (Box 4, Folder 81)
        Tinker 104
      - ALS to Charles Eliot Norton, Ambleside, [1882] Aug 31 (Box 4, Folder 82)
        Tinker 107
      - ALS to John William Parker, [London], 1860 Jun 1 (Box 4, Folder 83)
        Tinker 108
      - ALS to John William Parker, [London], 1860 Dec 5 (Box 4, Folder 84)
        Tinker 109
      - ALS to John William Parker, Jr., London, 1855 Mar 20 (Box 4, Folder 85)
        Tinker 110
      - ALS to John William Parker, Jr., London, 1855 Apr 11 (Box 4, Folder 86)
        Tinker 111
      - ALS to Mark Pattison, London, [1879] (Box 4, Folder 87)
        Tinker 112
      - ALS to John Payne, Harrow, 1871 Jun 28 (Box 4, Folder 88)
        Tinker 113
      - ALS to Lady Richardson, Ambleside, 1879 Sep 10 (Box 4, Folder 89)
        Tinker 114
      - ALS to George Washburn Smalley, Cobham, Surrey, [1885] Sep 26 (Box 4, Folder 90)
        Tinker 115
      - ALS to George Washburn Smalley, Cobham, Surrey, n.y. Oct 28 (Box 4, Folder 91)
        Tinker 116
      - Addressed envelope to Mrs. Whitridge, New York City, 1885 Oct (Box 4, Folder 92)
        Tinker 119
      - ALS to Lucy Charlotte (Arnold) Whitridge, Cobham, Surrey, 1885 Oct 13 (Box 4, Folder 93)
        Tinker 120
      - ALS to John Carvell Williams, [London], 1872 Mar 14 (Box 4, Folder 94)
        Tinker 121
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent, [London], 1871 Mar 20 (Box 4, Folder 95)
        Tinker 123
      - Broadside entitled "Vanity Fair. Nov. 11, 1871. Men of the Day, No. 36"; Printed article entitled "Men of the Day. No. 36. Mr. Matthew Arnold."; Photograph of Arnold [facsimile?]., 1871, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - "B"
    - Baratier, J. P. (Jean Philippe), 1721-1740
      - ALS to Elizabeth Carter, Halle, 1739 Feb 24 (Box 4, Folder 97)
        In French Tinker 211
      - ALS to Elizabeth Carter, Halle, 1739 Aug 12 (Box 4, Folder 98)
        In Latin and French Tinker 212
    - Bath, William Pulteney, Earl of, 1684-1764
      - ANS to Mrs. Elizabeth (Robinson) Montagu, London, 1764 Jan 6 (Box 4, Folder 99)
        Tinker 219
    - Beattie, James, 1735-1803
      - ALS to John Carr, Gordon Castle, 1782 Jun 13 (Box 4, Folder 100)
        Tinker 220
    - Beerbohm, Max, Sir, 1872-1956
      - ALS to Mr. Drummond, London, 1900 Jul 11 (Box 4, Folder 101)
        Enclosure: "A provisional list of the coloured caricatures." Tinker 224
    - Beers, Henry Augustin, 1847-1926
      - ALS to Mr. Reed, New Haven, 1895 Jul 1 (Box 4, Folder 102)
      - 2 ALS to Mr. Stedman, New Haven, 1895-98 (Box 4, Folder 103)
      - AMS poem, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Bell, Mackenzie, 1856-1930
      - ALS to Mr. Foster, London, 1907 Jan 11 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Bell, Robert, 1800-1867
      - ALS to William Harrison Ainsworth, London, [1849?] Aug 8 (Box 4, Folder 106)
        Tinker 245
      - ALS to W. H. Ainsworth, London, n.y. [Jun 8?] (Box 4, Folder 107)
      - AL in the third person to Mr. Churchill, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Bellew, John Chippendall Montesquieu, 1823-1874
      - 3 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, 1862-63, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 109)
        Letter dated 1863 Mar 25 refers to "the first pedigree of Shakespeare's family, in full, that has ever been compiled." Accompanied by an engraving of a photograph of Bellew by D. J. Pound.
    - Benger, E. (Elizabeth), 1778-1827
      - ALS in the third person to C. Orme, London (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Bentley, George, 1828-1895
      - ALS to Frederick Bentley, Blackheath, London (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Bentley, Richard, 1794-1871
      - 5 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1855-61 (Box 4, Folder 112)
        Tinker 246
    - Besant, Walter, 1836-1901
      - ALS to Mr. Simpson, London, 1871 Feb 25 (Box 4, Folder 113)
        Tinker 247
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1875 Nov 4 (Box 4, Folder 114)
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1876 Jan 10 (Box 4, Folder 115)
      - ALS to unidentified recipient, Hampstead, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Bessborough, Henrietta Frances Spencer Ponsonby, Countess of, 1761-1821
      - ALS to Francis Cohen, 1820 Jul (Box 4, Folder 117)
        [i.e., to Sir Francis Palgrave]
    - Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943
      - ALS to Richard Alexander Streatfeild, Chicago, 1912 Nov 25 (Box 4, Folder 118)
        Tinker 249
      - ALS to Richard Alexander Streatfeild, Baden-Baden, n.y. Apr 23 (Box 4, Folder 119)
        Tinker 250
    - Birkbeck, Morris, 1764-1825
      - ALS to William Phillips, Wanborough, 1814 Nov 8 (Box 4, Folder 120)
        Brief biographical note, in another hand, inside first page.
    - Birrell, Augustine, 1850-1933
      - ALS to Sir James Matthew Barrie, London, 1931 Dec (Box 4, Folder 121)
        Tinker 251
    - Black, William, 1841-1898
      - Autograph and closing lines of letter (Box 4, Folder 122)
        Accompanied by photograph of Black
    - Blackburn, Henry, 1830-1897
      - 2 ALS to Henry Hepworth Dixon, London, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Blackett, Henry, 1826?-1871
      - ALS to Henry Hepworth Dixon, London, 1863 Jul 10 (Box 4, Folder 124)
        Tinker 256
    - Blackwood, William, 1776-1834
      - ALS to William Jerdan, Edinburgh, 1827 Jan 16 (Box 4, Folder 125)
        Tinker 257
    - Blair, Hugh, 1718-1800
      - ALS to [John Syme?], Summerfield, 1797 Sep 12 (Box 4, Folder 126)
        Tinker 258
    - Blake, William, 1757-1827
      - "Affection and Love", pencil drawing (Box 4a, Folder 127)
        Tinker 259
      - "Nor fox, nor wolf, nor rot among our sheep", pencil and pen-and-ink drawing (Box 4a, Folder 128)
        Tinker 260
      - "The Book of my Remembrance", plate 21 from A Small Book of Designs printed by Blake at Lambeth, 1795-96 (Box 4a, Folder 129)
        Tinker 261
      - "Does the Soul labour thus" "In Caverns of the Grave", plate 15 from A Small Book of Designs printed by Blake at Lambeth, 1795-96 (Box 4a, Folder 130)
        Tinker 262
      - ALS to John Flaxman, London, 1800 Sep 21 (Box 4a, Folder 130a)
        General note
        Accompanied by typed transcription, facsimile print of the letter, and an etching of Blake's at cottage at Felpham, after a drawing by Herbert H. Gilchrist, taken from The Life of William Blake, by Alexander Gilchrist (London: Macmillan, 1880)
        Tinker 264
    - Blessington, Marguerite, Countess of, 1789-1849
      - Two pages of AL, unsigned, to Lord [Robert?] Jocelyn, Gow House, 1835 Aug 20 (Box 4a, Folder 131)
        Accompanied by manuscript copy of verses by Lord Jocelyn (autograph of Lady Blessington pasted to verses) and a portrait of Lady Blessington.
    - Bohn, Henry George, 1796-1884
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1861 Jan 22 (Box 4a, Folder 132)
    - Borlase, Edmund, d. 1682?
      - 2 ALS (copies) to an undentified recipient, 1656 Oct 10 (Box 4a, Folder 133)
    - Boswell family
      - Engravings and facsimiles of portraits (Box 4a, Folder 134)
    - Boswell, James, 1778-1822
      - [Not worth an epitaph by Tate or Quarles...], n.d. (Box 4a, Folder 135)
        Poem in the hand of James Boswell. The signature is in an unidentified hand. Tinker 365 For other Boswell manuscripts, see the Boswell Collection, GEN MSS 89.
    - Boteler, William Fuller, 1777-1845
      - ALS to Sir Samuel Egerton Brydges, Eastry, 1803 Jan 3 (Box 4a, Folder 136)
    - Bourne, Vincent, 1695-1747
      - ALS to Jacob Tonson, London (Box 4a, Folder 137)
        Sends two poems: "Upon Ben Johnson's Club-Room Called the Apollo at the Devil Tavern in Fleet Street" and "An Epitaph." Tinker 368
    - Bowles, Thomas Gibson, 1841-1922
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1872 Jan 19 (Box 4a, Folder 138)
    - Bray, Charles, 1811-1884
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Rosehill, 1846 May 30 (Box 4a, Folder 139)
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Teignmouth, 1846 Oct 15 (Box 4a, Folder 140)
    - Braybrooke, Richard Griffin, Baron, 1783-1853
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London, n.y. Jul 17 (Box 4a, Folder 141)
        Sends address of H. Weekes, 2 Belgrave Place, Pimlico.
    - Brewer, J. S. (John Sherren), 1810-1879
      - 2 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, 1862, n.d. (Box 4a, Folder 142)
    - Brierley, Benjamin, 1825-1896
      - ALS to Miss Sharples, Manchester, 1883 Feb 5 (Box 4a, Folder 143)
        Encloses two lines of verse and his autograph.
    - Broughton, John Cam Hobhouse, Baron, 1786-1869
      - ALS to Fuller, London, n.y. Jul 29 (Box 4a, Folder 144)
        Paper watermarked 1833. Removed from: Lord Byron's Hours of Idleness (Newark, 1807).
    - Brown, James Baldwin, 1820-1884
      - ALS to Mr. Boyd, Windsor, [18]53 May 12 (Box 4a, Folder 145)
    - Browning, Elizabeth Barrett, 1806-1861
      - Fragment of an ALS, [1840 Jun 1] (Box 4a, Folder 146)
        With 20th century manuscript copy of entire letter
      - AMS of two poems, n.d. (Box 4a, Folder 147)
    - Browning, Robert, 1812-1889
      - AMS of "Cavalier Tunes", n.d. (Box 4a, Folder 148)
        Tinker 407
      - ALS to Mrs. Lewes (George Eliot), London, 1863 Aug 2 (Box 5, Folder 149)
        Tinker 409
      - ALS to Elliott Warburton, New Cross, Hatcham, Surrey, 1846 Jul 29 (Box 5, Folder 150)
        Tinker 410
    - Brownrigg, John
      - Manuscript itemized bill to [Thomas Sheridan], 1763 (Box 5, Folder 151)
        Bill from shoemaker Tinker 1913
    - Bruce, J. Collingwood (John Collingwood), 1805-1892
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1857 Aug 18 (Box 5, Folder 152)
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London (Box 5, Folder 153)
        Possibly 1859 or 1860 Tinker 439
    - Bryce, James Bryce, Viscount, 1838-1922
      - ALS to Mr. Creighton, London, n.y. Jul 15 (Box 5, Folder 154)
      - 2 ALS to J. C. Schwab, Dublin, N.H., 1910 (Box 5, Folder 155)
    - Buchan, John, 1875-1940
      - TLS to A. Edward Newton, Oxford, 1924 Dec 23 (Box 5, Folder 156)
        Thanking him for a booklet on John Mytton
    - Bullen, George, 1816-1894
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1860 Jul 23 (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - Burnand, F. C. (Francis Cowley), Sir, 1836-1917
      - ALS to T. Paynter Allen, London, 1883 Jun 5 (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, Sir, 1833-1898
      - ALS to [Henschel?], London (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Bury, Charlotte Campbell, Lady, 1775-1861
      - ALS to Mr. Bentley, n.y. Feb 13 (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - Byron, George Gordon Byron, Baron, 1788-1824
      - AMS of "Childish recollection", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 161)
        Tinker 475
      - AMS of English bards and Scotch reviewers (Box 5, Folder 162)
        Tinker 476
      - AMS of "Epitaph for Mr. Joseph Blacket late poet & shoemaker", 1811 May 16 (Box 5, Folder 163)
        Tinker 477
      - AMS of "Four or Five reasons in favour of a change", 1811 (Box 5, Folder 164)
        Tinker 478
      - AMS of "Translation of the Romaic song", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 165)
        Includes ANS from Joseph Parkes to Bessie Rayner (Parkes) Belloc, Westminster, 1847 Dec 14. Presenting the ms to his daughter. Includes inscribed envelope by Joseph Parkes, Westminster, 1847 Dec 14. Recording the gift of the ms to him by the Hon. Mrs. Leigh. Tinker 479
      - AMS of "Again decieved! again betrayed!", 1812 (Box 5, Folder 166)
        Tinker 480
      - AMS of four lines of the The Giaour, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 167)
        Tinker 481
      - AMS of "I wander near that fount of waters", 1814 Apr 15 (Box 5, Folder 168)
        Bound with ALS to Lady Sarah Caroline (Stovin) Sitwell, [London], 1814 Apr 15 Tinker 482, Tinker 503